James Bergen

16340 Hanna Rd. | Lutz, FL 33549 | Phone: 631-921-2286 | jmbergen922@gmail.com

Objective

I am a hard working and detailed oriented software developer with automated and manual testing experience. I love writing code and solving problems. I'm hoping to find a position that is exciting and will also allow me to develop my skills and grow professionally.

Technical Skills

Programming/Web: Ruby, C#, JavaScript, VB.NET, ASP.NET, Sinatra, HTML, CSS, Slim

Database/DBMS: SQL, MS SQL Server 2012

Tools: Cucumber, Selenium WebDriver, NUnit, WATIR, Visual Studio

2012, TFS, SVN

Professional Experience

Bisk

Software Quality Assurance Engineer I

February 2016 - Present

- Build and maintain an automation framework using C#, Selenium WebDriver and NUnit
- Created build verification and regression tests for the Learning Management System and marketing sites
- Conduct peer code reviews
- Assist with manual testing and report any defects for development team to address

West Point Underwriters Software Development Engineer in Test January 2013 – February 2016

- Created automation scripts for regression testing utilizing Ruby, WATIR and Cucumber
- Designed and implemented new tools for QA Automation such as a rating utility, force renewals tool, and environment dashboard
- Trained new hires on QA Automation process and tools
- Led IT department lunch and learns to review QA Automation process
- Implemented bug fixes and re-factored code for existing QA tools
- Provided technical support for QA team

West Point Underwriters QA Analyst April 2012 – January 2013

- Interpreted requirements and applied business logic to create test cases
- Identified defects and provided detailed documentation with steps to recreate
- Worked with SDET to maintain automation scripts utilizing Ruby, WATIR and Cucumber

Education

University of South Florida, Tampa, FL Bachelor of Science in Management Information Systems May 2011